Guillermo Paz

Front End Developer

About me

I am a proactive and creative front end developer. I am currently working at MercadoLibre at Buenos Aires, Argentina.

I enjoy taking advantage of awesome new browser features without breaking the experience on older browser. I am up to date with IT trends and innovation. I really love to experiment with new web technologies, APIs and standards.

I write semantic HTML and CSS code that works perfectly on all modern browsers. I love JavaScript and I know its good parts. I keep a close eye on JavaScript development client and server side, user interfaces, interaction design, web technologies and web standards.

I've been developing clean, valid and compatible websites, libraries and UI widgets since the last 5 years. I am skilled to define and maintain well crafted, complex and large libraries.

Personal Details

Birth: May 28, 1988

Address: Buenos Aires, Argentina E-mail: guille87paz@gmail.com Website: http://pazguille.me

Professional Experience

2008-Present	Frontend Developer - MercadoLibre I'm a Front End Developer at MercadoLibre. I build Chico UI (MercadoLibre's UI framework). I review the front end code. Beside, I research the best practices and teach them to others front end teams to improve their code. I give speeches about web standards, best practices and how to improve your frontend code.
2007-Present	Independent web developer, front end developer. Training and doing workshops about open web standards. Occasionally freelancing.
2007–2008	Customer Service - MercadoLibre

Specialties

I have a broad understanding of the full Open Web Stack of technologies:

Expert level knowledge of the JavaScript language.

- Expert level knowledge of jQuery.
- Expert understanding of web technologies (object-oriented JavaScript, HTML, CSS).
- Expert level knowledge of HTML y CSS.
- Expert at writing semantic and well formed HTML.
- Experience at developing JavaScript libraries.
- Experience at writing vanilla Javascript.
- Experience with JavaScript libraries (jQuery, Modernizr, Backbone, Underscore).
- Experience with the latest and greatest web standards, including HTML5 and CSS3 (W3C).
- Experience at working with REST APIs.
- Experience at testing and developing across multiple browsers while maintaining a consistent experience.
- Experience at working with graceful degradation y progressive enhancement.
- Experience with Responsive Web Design.
- Experience with NodeJS, Express, Jade, SocketIO and Mongoose.
- Experience with GIT (I absolutely love Github).

Education

2008–2011 Tertiary education	Designer and Web Site Manager. Da Vinci - Multimedial Art Institute.
2006–2007	First year of Licentiate in Systems Analysis . University of Buenos Aires.
2001–2005	Assistant to work in Social Communication. Ana María Janer Secondary School.

Honors and Awards

August 2012	Winner of Facebook Developers World Hack Latin America 2012. The best
	overall application of Latin America - Buenos Aires, Argentina.

Projects

November 2012	Viewport : It is a component to ease viewport management. You can get the dimensions of the viewport and beyond, which can be quite helpful to perform some checks with JavaScript.
May 2012	Jvent: Event Emitter Class for the browser based on NodeJS EventEmitter.
June 2009	Chico UI : MercadoLibre's a big and complex web site with a lot of needs. Every development and design team needed to be able to build quality and consistent web apps using an agile development process. So we had to find a way to unify the process and guarantee design pattern and user experience quality for every team. And Chico was born.

More of my open source libraries and projects can be found in my Github account.

Speaking

May 2012

I gave a speech at **JSconf Argentina** about Chico UI and how it helps MercadoLibre to improve its code using the best practices of frontend and progressive enhancement.

Languages

Spanish: Native

• English: Intermediate

Professional interests

- Open web standards
- Front-end architecture
- Web Usability & Accessibility
- Web Development Education
- API design
- Graphic Design